翻译校对       Mam
日  听      マキ
日听校对       Syura
翻译        小袖
时间轴       黑猫与牛奶
压制      娜夏
OP&ED       葉隠
Syura
诸神字幕组
"Pension Misuzu"
ハルヒって　藤岡ハルヒ？
Haruhi? Fujioka Haruhi?
あっ　荒井君
Arai- kun!
Um, friends of yours?
えっと　友達？
Mm-hmm, this is Hikaru and Kaoru.
うん　高校で同じクラスの光と馨
They're in the same class as me
in high school. And this...
それとこちらは
...is my senpa-
先輩…　あっ
Haruhi, while you are in training here,
ハルヒは合宿中　俺を先輩扱いしないこと
you are not to treat me as your Senpai.
...is an acquaintance of mine.
知り合いの人
"No offense intended"
Misuzu- san...
付けないでください
Please don't go adding any sound effects
of your own to my despair.
It's been since our graduation ceremony
from middle school, huh?
中学の卒業式以来だね
You've cut your hair. That's such a shame.
髪切っちゃったんだ　勿体無いなぁ
そうかな　切っちゃえば　こっちのほうが楽でいいよ
You think so? After cutting it,
it's easier to manage this way.
Have you settled in at Ouran?
桜蘭には慣れた？
Do you ever see anyone from middle school?
中学ん時のやつらには　会ったりしてんの？
Mm-hmm, sort of. Kazumi
calls me a lot, and such.
まあまあ　和美とかはよく電話くれるよ
Hmm, he's a friend of Haruhi
from middle school, is he?
ハルヒの中学時代の友人か
If he's had zero contact since graduation,
卒業以来連絡ゼロなんて
he's not a friend,
he's just a former classmate.
友達じゃなくて ただの元同級生じゃん
You say they're in the same club
as you are. What club is that?
同じ部活の人たちって　何部
ホスト部
The Host Club.
Oh yeah? The softball club, huh?
へぇぇ　ソフト部か
Hey, Haruhi! Shouldn't you be working?
おい　ハルヒ　仕事しなくていいわけ
We've got a goldbricker over here!
サボりの人がいますよ
Misuzu- san let me have a break.
美鈴さんが休憩くれたんだよ
先輩　ゴミ増やすのやめてくれませんか
Senpai, could you not make
any more garbage, please?
It's not garbage.
I'm making a hamster home.
ゴミじゃないもん　ハムスターのお家だもん
Senpai, you don't have a hamster, right?
先輩ハムスター飼ってないでしょう
先輩じゃないもん
I'm not your senpai.
I'm just an acquaintance.
ただの知り合いの人だもん
You Ouran folks are so funny!
面白いな　桜蘭の人って
It's such an elite school. I imagined
it was like a whole different world.
すごいエリート学校だし　世界違うってイメージだったけど
It's other-dimensional enough.
十分異次元だよ
The truth is, Fujioka, I was
worried that if you went there,
本当はそんなとこ行って
藤岡が苦労してるんじゃないかって心配してたんだけどさ
you'd probably have a hard time of it.
I'm glad to see you're doing so well.
元気そうでよかったよ
Uh, er, but I'm not
the only one who was worried,
でも　心配っても　別に俺だけじゃなくて
他のやつらもだけど
the other guys were saying so, too.
What's with this guy? Is he taking
the refreshing innocence line?
なんじゃありゃ　爽やか純情路線狙ってんのか
We ended the refreshment contest
last episode, you know.
爽やか勝負は前回で終わってるっつうの
You're being unusually critical, aren't you?
先から妙に絡むな
I'm just saying,
つーかさ　そいつ　あからさまにハルヒに気があんじゃん
that guy is clearly interested in Haruhi.
It's plain as day, and kind of sickening.
みえみえでなんか嫌な感じ
Now hold on, Hikaru!
ちょっと光　先から感じ悪いのそっちじゃん
You're the one who's been
acting unpleasant here!
いいよいいよ　藤岡に気があったのは本当だし
No, it's okay. He's right, I did
have a thing for you, Fujioka.
つっても　俺　すでに振られてんだけどね
Then again, I've already been
turned down by you.
Why are you so surprised?
なぜお前が驚く
えっ　いや　だって
Well, I mean...
Arai- kun, was it?
When are we talking about, here?
荒井君とやら　それはいつ頃のことかね
It was about a year ago, now.
もう　一年ぐらい前ですよ
"Middle school, 3rd Year- summer"
There she is!
いた　藤岡
Fujioka!
I heard you were taking
the honor student exam for Ouran.
聞いたよ　桜蘭の特待生試験　受けるんだって
Mm-hmm.
You are? With your grades,
Fujioka, it's quite possible.
そっか　藤岡の成績ならありだよな
Although, I was sure you'd be
going to Higashi High, and all...
でも　てっきり東高行くんだと思ってたからさ
I'm testing for Higashi High, too.
東高も一緒に受けるよ　桜蘭受かるか分かんないし
I don't know if I'll be accepted
to Ouran, after all.
Yeah. But I guess I'll have to cheer you on.
いや　でも　応援しなきゃだよな
I would have liked to go to
the same high school, though.
同じ高校行けたらって思ってたけど
Then, you should have said something sooner.
なら　早く言ってくれればよかったのに
You mean...
それって？
I think Ouran's honor student consideration
桜蘭の特待生枠って　一人じゃなかったと思うよ
applies for more than just one person.
Oh, that...
そっちか
"That?"
もし　定員が一名でも
And even if it is only for one person,
you can't give up on going
to the school you want to
人に気を使って行きたい高校諦めちゃダメだよ
for someone else's sake.
Even if only one of us gets in,
どっちかしか受からなくても
there's no hard feelings
over entrance exams, right?
恨みっこなしが受験でしょう
We should both do our best.
お互い頑張らなきゃ
I know, let's go check with the teacher.
そうだ　先生に確認してもらおうよ
あの　藤岡
Fujioka!
あ…あの　付き合ってほしいんだけど
U-um... I want you to go with me!
Mm-hmm...
I'd like to check the
application deadline, too.
私も願書の締め切り確認したいし 一緒に職員室行こう？
Let's go to the staff room together.
"Saw that one coming"
Haruhi...
ハルヒ
You crushed this poor young man's innocence
お前そんな下手なボケでいたいけな少年の純情を？
over such a trite, throwaway gag?
- No, you see, I didn't realize
that's what he meant at all...
- This is a serious crime, huh?
いえ　だからそういう意味とはまったく気付かず…
I'm sorry.
"A reply, one year later"
ごめんなさい
Huh? You don't mean,
you're turning me down again, now?
もしかしたら今　改めて振られてんの　俺
No, that's okay, that's okay,
I've gotten over it already.
いや　いいよいいよ　もう吹っ切れてるし
If you didn't realize what I meant,
it shows you weren't interested.
気付かなかったってことは興味なかったってことだし
Still, Fujioka, that gentle,
yet awfully faraway look in your eyes...
けど俺は
藤岡の大人しそうだけど
なんかすごく遠くを見つめてる目とか
...and the way you look directly
at someone when you talk to them...
話す時　相手をまっすぐ見るとことか
I've always thought that was
something great about you.
そういうのずっと　いいなって思ってたんだ
You think that much about my little girl?
うちの子のことをそこまで…
Don't you worry, I shall
never forget your gallantry!
安心しろ　君の勇姿は忘れない
You went to Kyoto on your
middle school field trip?
中学の修学旅行は京都だったの
It's so unusual that it
would be in-country, huh?
国内なんて珍しいね
No, that's normal, for commoners.
いや　普通っすよ　庶民なら
Mm-hmm, I like Kyoto, too.
うん　俺も京都は好きだぞ
I often had to accompany this guy
when he toured the temples.
俺も　こいつの趣味でよく寺めぐりに付き合わされる
Hikaru, what should we do?
光　どうする
向こう盛り上がってるけど　混ざる？
They're having a good time over there.
Should we join them?
Nah, he's annoying. His highness
just took to him so easily.
いいよ　うぜぇ
殿も簡単に懐いちゃって　アホじゃねぇの
What is he, stupid?
Hey, Hikaru, Kaoru!
光　馨
You guys come on over, too!
This is a rare chance
お前らも来い
ハルヒの中学時代のエピソードが聞ける貴重な機会だぞ
to hear some episodes from
Haruhi's middle-school days!
I don't especially want to hear about them.
別に聞きたくありません
つーか　バカじゃないの
Or should I say, how stupid are you?
I can't understand why
you would get so excited
なんでそんな過去の話とか聞いて盛り上がれるのか意味分かんない
over hearing stories about the past.
そいつもさ　ハルヒに相手にされてないって　分かんないわけ？
And doesn't he get that Haruhi
doesn't want anything to do with him?
Haruhi doesn't have
any room for you in her life!
ハルヒん中に　お前の入る場所なんてないっつうの
That's not up to you to decide, Hikaru!
そんなの　光が決めることじゃないよ
If you do one more rude thing
to my friend, you'll answer to me!
人の友達にこれ以上失礼なことするなら　許さないから
What is this? What do other people matter?
何だよ　他のやつの事なんてどうでもいいだろ
We're your friends, aren't we!?
お前の友達は　俺らじゃんか
光　待ってってば
Hikaru! Wait up!
Their world is still so small, huh?
まだまだ世界が狭いな　あいつらは
Wow, that was pretty hot-headed.
Growing pains?
なになに　熱いね　青春？
Kaoru, you were disgusted, too.
馨だってムカついてたくせに
I still think I was more
rational than you, Hikaru.
光よりは理性あると思うけど
The way you threw your
selfish feelings around like that
あんな自分勝手な感情のぶつけ方してっちゃ
was pretty childish. Haruhi was stunned.
まるで子供だよ
ハルヒだって呆れる
What am I supposed to do?
しょうがないだろう
I was just incredibly disgusted,
and I'm not even sure why.
なんか知らないけど　すげぇムカついたんだ
For now, how about going down
and apologizing to Arai- kun?
とりあえず　あの荒井君に謝っとこうよ
Arai- kun, I'm sorry.
荒井君　ごめんね
It's okay. I don't know what I did,
but it somehow seemed to set him off.
いいよ　よく分かんないけど
なんか俺も気に障ることしちゃったみたいだし
Hika-chan...
ヒカちゃん
I was out of line.
悪かった　ごめん
Sorry.
Nah, it's okay.
うん　いいって
じゃな　藤岡
Bye now, Fujioka.
See you later, everyone.
皆もまた
Bye-bye!
バイバ～イ
Kaoru, why are you pretending to be Hikaru?
馨　なんで光のふりしてるわけ？
Hey, where's that scratch on your cheek?
ちょっと　頬辺の傷は？
イテテテ…スティックコンシーラーでちょちょいっとね
I touched it up with some stick concealer.
Hikaru doesn't seem like
he'll cheer up anytime soon.
光の機嫌　まだ治りそうになくてさ
And so, Haruhi, I have
a small favor to ask of you.
つきましては　ハルヒ　ちょっと頼みがあるんだけど
All day tomorrow, would you
go out on a date with me?
明日一日　僕とデートしてくんない？
Sorry to keep you waiting.
お待たせ
Huh?
あれ　馨は？
Where's Kaoru?
Well, you see...
それが…
Yesterday, to apologize for
being rude to Haruhi's friend,
昨日ハルヒのお友達に悪いことしたお詫びに
I agreed to meet Haruhi today,
but now it looks like I've caught a cold.
ハルヒと待ち合わせしてたんだけど
風引いちゃったみたいで…
Are you okay?
大丈夫なの？
光が代わりに行ってきて
Hikaru, you go in my place.
Today, you have to escort
Haruhi until this evening,
今日は夕方までハルヒが楽しく過ごせるようにエスコートすること
and make sure that she has a good time.
It has to go well, Hikaru,
or she'll never speak to you again.
うまくやらなきゃもう光とは口きかないから
Can you do that?
できるね
Yeah, I can do that.
そりゃできるけどさ
Really?
本当に？
What? You saying I can't?
何だよ　無理だってんの
You've never really gone out
with anyone else before, Hikaru.
これまでちゃんと他人と付き合ったことないだろ　光は
Okay, listen closely.
いい　よく聞いて
You have to make sure to tell
other people what you're feeling,
お互いの気持ちとかは言わなきゃ相手には伝わらない
or it won't get through to them. However...
What were you thinking, Kaoru?
何考えてんだ　馨
What do we do? Should we go back?
どうしよう　帰る？
No, I'll go out with you today,
in his place.
イヤ　今日は僕が代理で付き合うから
それより　その格好…
That aside, though, what's with this getup?
Is it weird?
変かな
No.
Haruhi!
ハルヒっ…
ちょっと　殿　見つかっちゃうって
Sir, they'll see us!
Why should I have to let
Haruhi and Hikaru have a date!?
なんでハルヒを光なんかとデートさせにゃならんのだ
After yesterday's events,
how did it turn out like this!?
昨日の流れで何故こういう展開になる
This could be Haru-chan's first date, huh?
ハルちゃん　初デートかもしれないね
ああ　許すまじ　光
Aah! I'll get you for this, Hikaru!
And what's with that outfit!?
大体なんなんだあの格好は
She's hyper-cute! Hyper-cute!
超可愛い　もう超可愛い
Oh, that was...
ああ　あれは…
- Good morning, Fujioka-sama.
おはようございます　藤岡さま
Huh?
- Come, let's get you ready.
さ　ご用意を…
Hey! What are you doing!?
ちょっと　何するんですか
No fair! No fair! No fair!
ずるい　ずるい　ずるい…
You know, sir, I think it
would be very good for Hikaru
あのさ　殿
僕は光に大事な物が増えるのってすごくいいことだと思うんだよね
to have more people who are dear to him.
For the longest time, the only people
who were dear to us were ourselves.
僕らはずっと自分たちしか大事じゃなかったからさあ
We felt like it didn't matter
what anyone else thought of us,
他人にはどう思われてもいいって感じだったから
and that's how we got our
self-centered disposition.
こんな好き勝手な性格になったわけ
And you realized it?
自覚はあったのか
Hikaru is especially childish, so he
charges into things on just emotion.
光なんか特にお子様だから
感情だけで突っ走っちゃうの
Still, although Hikaru
doesn't seem to be aware of it,
でも　光は自覚ないみたいだけど
he's become quite fond of Haruhi.
ハルヒのことはかなり気に入ってんだよ
He just doesn't know how to act,
ただ　自分の感じを押し付けるやり方しか知らないから
except to force his
own feelings onto others,
so he becomes monopolizing, like a child.
子供染みた独占欲になっちゃう
お前の友達は俺らじゃんか
We're your friends, aren't we!?
Even when he wants to be
acknowledged by someone,
相手に認めてほしいと思ってても
he doesn't know what he should do.
どうやったらいいか分からないんだ
If you want to have true friends,
and not just toys,
おもちゃじゃなくて　本当の友達になりたいなら
you have to respect
the other person, don't you?
相手も尊重しなきゃダメじゃん
I think that Hikaru needs to learn exactly
そういうちゃんとした他人との付き合い方ってのを
光はきっちり学ばなきゃいけないって思うわけ
how to get along with
other people in that way.
Kaoru, you're amazing.
馨　すごいな　お前は
So what you're saying is that
this date is a trial,
つまりこのデートは
光に相手を思いやる気持ちを芽生えさせる試練なわけか
to get Hikaru to foster feelings
of consideration for someone else.
So make sure you don't
interfere with them, okay?
だから絶対に邪魔しないでよね
Then, we don't need to
be tailing them, do we?
なら尾行などしなければいいのでは？
Sure we do.
いや　だって　こんな面白いこと見ないではないじゃん
There's no reason for us not to watch
something this interesting, is there?
So, Haruhi, where do you want to go?
で　ハルヒはどこに行きたいの
Kaoru said he would show me around,
馨が案内してくれるって言ったから
so I haven't thought of anything.
You, Hikaru?
何も考えてなかった　光は？
I've got nothing I need
to do in Karuizawa now.
いまさら軽井沢に用なんか…
ちゃんとエスコートすること
Make sure you're escorting her.
Okay, how about the outlet mall
in front of the train station?
じゃさ　駅前のアウトレットモールは？
They have cheap clothes there.
服とか安いとこ
Fine with me. Hikaru, you want some clothes?
いいけど　光服ほしいの？
No, we don't buy anything there.
いや　僕はそんなとこじゃ買わないけど…
"Hikaru's idea of being considerate"
I don't really need anything.
別にいらない
"...swing and a miss"
What a pain.
めんどくせぇ
Misuzu- san said that
the weather might not hold.
天気崩れるかもって美鈴さん言ってたよ
I sure hope there aren't any thunderstorms.
雷雨とかじゃなきゃいいんだけど
Who cares about the weather?
天気なんかどうでもいいんだよ
"Annoyance"
Aah! What a tedious date this is!
なんつーウキドキ感のないデートなんだ
As stiff as you're acting,
you call yourself a Host Club member!?
ギスギスしよってそれでもホスト部員か
替われ　光
Switch with me, Hikaru!
I'll escort her instead!
俺が代わりにエスコートして
Then there wouldn't be any meaning!
それじゃ意味ないって
Then, Kyoya, you go make like a punk,
and pick a fight with Haruhi!
じゃ　鏡夜
ハルヒに絡むちんぴらの役　やって来い
That will let Hikaru rescue her!
そこに光に助けさせる
Wait until you're asleep
to dream this stuff up.
寝言は寝て言え
"Honey's idea for softening the situation"
Ice cream! Ice cream!
Anyone want ice cream!?
アイス　アイス　アイスはいらんかね
"Ice cream"
"Honey's idea for softening the situation"
Don't.
止めとけ
Didn't that old coot just now
look sort of like Honey- senpai?
今のおっさん　なんかハニー先輩に似てなかっ…
"Unexpected"
Huh?
アイスください
Ice cream, please.
Hey, Haruhi! Don't go off on your own!
コラ　ハルヒ　なに勝手に
I hear the ice cream here is famous. Here.
ここのアイス有名なんだって
はい　一口お先にどうぞ
You take the first bite.
If it's no good, there'll be a penalty game.
まずかったら罰ゲームな
可愛いね　お嬢ちゃん　ほら　もう一個サービスだホイ
What a cute young lady!
Here's one more, on the house.
Thank you.
ありがとう
Delicious!
おいしい
確かに　意外にうまい
You're right, it is better than I expected.
It was finally going well!
What are you interfering for!?
せっかくいい感じだったのに　何邪魔してんのだ
あのう…
- You idiot! You think I'm going
to let them couple-eat!?
- Um...
馬鹿者
"The real clerk"
あんなカップル食いが許されると思うのか
No indirect kissing!
間接チュー　反対
It says these are pickled yams.
That's unusual, huh?
山芋の漬物だって　珍しいね
Pickled food is so lame. Who even cares?
漬物なんてダサいもん　どうでもいいよ
Here.
Okay, so it's good...
うまいけど…
Well then, two bags of these, please.
じゃあ　これ二袋ください
Thanks, come again.
毎度どうも
If you're buying souvenirs,
shouldn't you wait until your last day?
お土産なら　最終日に買ったほうがいいんじゃないの
You're going to be in Karuizawa
for a while yet, right?
まだ当分軽井沢にいんだろう
These are a gift for Kaoru.
これはね　馨へのお土産
You know, we could all go on
an outing together later, couldn't we?
あのさ　遠出はまた皆ですればいいんじゃない
Let's check out the shops around here today,
今日はこの辺のお店覗いて　馨へのお土産選ぼうよ
and choose some gifts for Kaoru.
How can you tell that
I'm feeling anxious about Kaoru?
なんで分かんの　馨のことでいらいらしてるって
Just because.
適当
Come on, let's go.
さっ　行こう
We take our eyes off of them for a minute,
and they're doing fine, huh?
ちょっと目を離した隙にいい感じじゃん
It's questionable whether Hikaru is
the one doing the escorting, though.
光がエスコートしてるのかは怪しいがな
やっぱりアイス屋が和ませたのかね
I guess the ice cream stand
really did smooth things over.
No, I doubt it.
いや　違うだろ
Let's head back. If we're sloppy
and get found out here,
帰ろっか
ここで下手にバレても台無しだし
it will be all for nothing.
これ以上ここにいてはいけない人もいるし
There's someone who can't bear
to stay here any longer, too.
That looks like so much fun...
how nice... how nice...
楽しそう　いいな　いいな
今　なんか　鳴った？
Did you just hear something?
いや　聞こえなかったけど
No, I didn't hear anything.
It does look like
it's going to rain, though.
降りそうではあるね
Should we be heading back?
そろそろ帰る？
Mm-hmm.
Okay, let's head to the street
and flag down a cab.
じゃ　通り出てタクシー拾って…
Huh? Fujioka?
あれ　藤岡？
What are you up to?
何してんの
Arai- kun, what are you doing?
荒井君こそどうしたの
Oh, this is my uncle's store.
What are you, shopping?
いや　ここがおじさんの店なんだ
何　買い物？
Mm-hmm. But we were just leaving.
うん　でももう帰るとこ
Well, I'll send you back in our car.
Let me go ask my uncle.
じゃ　うちの車で送ってってやるよ
おじさんに頼んでやる
Oh, but we couldn't.
でも悪いよ
I heard some thunder,
and it's going to start raining soon, now.
雷鳴ってたし　この分じゃすぐ降るよ
That's okay, we're getting a taxi.
いいんだよ　タクシー拾うから
Oh, but the taxi fare
would be a waste of money.
ええ　タクシー代もったいないって
じゃ　お願いしよっか
Well, why don't we ask them?
The sooner we go, the better.
早いほうが嬉しいし
Haruhi, how about if just you were to go?
ハルヒだけ乗せてもらえば？
Hikaru...
光
Just do whatever you want to!
好きにしろって言ってんの
Then you can get chummy, and talk
all about the past or whatever!
そんで　仲良く昔話でも何でもすりゃいいじゃん
Hikaru!
光
Not again. Is he really that
bothered by old friends of yours?
またか
そんなに昔の友達とかイヤなのかな
He must have some of his own.
自分にだっているだろうに
生まれた時から一緒だし
We were together when we were born,
and we never had any other friends.
他に友達もいなかったし
That lightning is incredible.
すごい稲妻
I hope they're staying out of the rain.
ヒカちゃんたち　雨宿りしてるかな
Tamaki- kun can't settle down.
環君　落ち着かないわね
I'm just going to go pick them up.
俺　ちょっと迎えに
Yes, Pension Misuzu.
はい　ペンションみすず
荒井君　どうしたの
Arai- kun, what is it?
Eh? Haruhi-chan and Hikaru- kun?
えっ　ハルヒちゃんと光君が？
うん　うん　分かった
Got it. Hikaru- kun should have his cell
with him, so I'll try calling.
光君は携帯持ってるはずだから連絡してみるわ
It sounds like Hikaru- kun left Haruhi-chan
in front of Arai- kun's store,
なんか　荒井君の店の前で
光君がハルヒちゃんを置いて一人で帰っちゃったって
and headed back here on his own.
He said that Haruhi-chan took off after him,
その後　ハルヒちゃんが追いかけていったらしいんだけど
but then, this rain
started coming down, right?
すぐにこの雨が降り出したでしょう
That's when Arai- kun became worried,
and called over here.
それで荒井君が心配してかけてきてくれたの
Yeah, sir? Perfect timing.
Could you send a car around for me?
あっ　殿　ちょうどよかった　車回してくんない？
I couldn't catch any cabs.
タクシーが捕まらなくて
You stupid idiot! You just turn around
right now and find Haruhi!
バカヤロウ
いいからすぐに引き返してハルヒを探せ
What kind of person leaves a girl
out in the rain like this by herself!?
こんな雨の中　女の子を一人置いてくるやつがあるか
Listen to me, Haruhi is afraid of thunder!
いいか　ハルヒは雷が怖いんだ
When she hears thunder,
she's terrified, and can't move!
雷が鳴ると　怯えて動けなくなるんだぞ
Before you start indulging
your overgrown jealousy,
一人前にやきもち焼く前に　相手のことをもっと考えろ
think harder about what the
other person is going through!
What does that mean?
何だよ　それ
How was I supposed to know,
if she never told me?
そんなの　言われなきゃ知るわけないじゃん
I sure hope there aren't any thunderstorms.
雷雨とかじゃなきゃいいんだけど
今　なんか　鳴った？
Did you just hear something?
Well, why don't we ask them?
The sooner we go, the better.
じゃ　お願いしよっか
早いほうが嬉しいし
How was I supposed to tell
from that, you idiot!?
あんなんで分かるか　バカ
Haruhi? You in here, Haruhi?
ハルヒ
いんの　ハルヒ
Haruhi?
ハルヒ
You have to make sure to tell
other people what you're feeling,
お互いの気持ちとかは　言わなきゃ伝わらない
or it won't get through to them. However...
However, if you care for
the other person, sometimes,
でも相手のことを思うなら
時には　ほんの些細なヒントを見落とさないことも大切で
it's important not to miss the
subtle little hints that they drop.
How can you tell that
I'm feeling anxious about Kaoru?
なんで分かんの　馨のことでいらいらしてるって
Just because.
適当
Haruhi...
ハルヒ
Hika-
I'm sorry.
ごめん
I'm sorry. For running off and leaving you,
ごめんな　一人置き去りにしちゃって
and for saying such mean things
about your dear friend. I'm sorry.
大事な友達にひどいこと言って
ごめん
ありがとう
Thanks...
Hikaru...
光
I'm sorry.
ごめん
"The next day"
ちはーす
'lo!
Ah, Arai- kun!
あっ　荒井君
I brought a watermelon.
Ours are delicious, you know.
スイカ持ってきたよ
うちのは甘いんだから
That's a really big one!
すごい大きいね
It's impressive, to be sure.
確かに見事なものだ
Here.
Thanks.
ありがとう
By the way,
ところで
about your strategy for yesterday's date,
did you ever consider
昨日のデート作戦
勢いあまって恋愛感情が芽生える可能性とかは考えなかったのか
the possibility that
it might have gone too well,
and fostered feelings of love?
It's still too soon for that.
それはまだ早いでしょう
Hikaru is a dummy, and all.
光　バカだしね
おい　スイカ割り　スイカ割り
Hey! Melon-cutting! Melon-cutting!
Well, we do have a lot
of dummies in our club.
まっ　バカが多いからな　うちの部は
あれ　鏡夜先輩が予告で喋るなんて珍しいですよね
俺は自分にメリットがないことはしない主義だからな
Huh? Kyoya-senpai, it's so unusual
for you to speak during the preview, huh?
I make it a rule not to do anything
if there's nothing in it for me.
桜蘭高校ホストクラブ　来週も
Next time, "Kyoya's Reluctant Day Out"
お待ちしております
Ouran High School Host Club will
be waiting for you, next week!